updated: 4/22 Chad McKell

ABOUT

Address 9500 Gilman Dr MC 0099

La Jolla, CA 92093-0099

 $\begin{array}{lll} {\rm Phone} & & +1.661.289.4215 \\ {\rm Email} & & {\rm cmckell@ucsd.edu} \\ {\rm Website} & & {\rm chadmckell.com} \end{array}$

Summary I am a Ph.D. student at UC San Diego. In my research, I develop computational

and mathematical tools for acoustic simulation. Topics of interest include spatial audio, hearing science, elastodynamics, and differential geometry. My research has applications

in music, animation, virtual reality, and other fields.

EDUCATION

| 9/19- | University of California San Diego, Ph.D. in Computer Music |
|-------------|---|
| , | GPA: 4.0. Dissertation: Geometric Methods for Open-Boundary Wave Simulations. |
| | Advisors: Albert Chern and Miller Puckette. |
| | |
| 9/16-10/17 | University of Edinburgh, M.S. in Acoustics and Music Technology |
| 8/09-12/15 | Wake Forest University, M.S. in Physics |
| 6/02 - 8/09 | Brigham Young University, B.S. in Biophysics |

PROFESSIONAL EMPLOYMENT

| 8/21-3/22 | Meta, Reality Labs Research, Research Intern/Student Researcher (Acoustics) |
|--------------|---|
| 7/18 - 7/19 | Applied Research in Acoustics, R&D Scientist (Acoustics) |
| 9/12 - 12/12 | Bennett Aerospace, Engineering Intern |

ACADEMIC EMPLOYMENT

| 9/19- | University of California San Diego, Teaching Assistant/Researcher (Music) |
|------------|---|
| 9/12-12/12 | University of North Carolina School of the Arts, Adjunct Instructor (Physics) |
| 9/09-9/11 | Wake Forest University, Teaching Assistant (Physics) |
| 9/08-6/09 | Brigham Young University, Tutorial Lab Assistant (Physics) |
| 8/07-3/09 | Brigham Young University, Research Assistant (Philosophy) |

CONSULTING

| 5/18-5/18 | Moog Music : Audio effects development in C++ for digital sound synthesizers. |
|------------|--|
| 4/17-9/17 | Lofelt: DSP development and physics-based modeling for audio-haptic devices. |
| 10/14-8/16 | J.P. Morgan/Neovest: QA software development in Java for J.P. Morgan's investment |
| | trading platform, Neovest. |

PROFESSIONAL RESEARCH ACTIVITIES

8/21–3/22 Meta, Reality Labs Research, Research Intern/Student Researcher

La Jolla, California (remote). Research areas: acoustics, applied mathematics. Conducted computational acoustics research for virtual and augmented reality devices. Research topics included spatial audio, numerical simulation, parallel programming, and discrete complex analysis. Supervisor: Sebastian Prepeliță. Team Lead: Ravish Mehra.

7/18–7/19 Applied Research in Acoustics, R&D Scientist

Culpeper, Virginia. Research areas: acoustics, digital signal processing. Developed physics-based signal processing algorithms for naval sonar systems. Research topics included underwater acoustics, matched filtering, sparse estimation, and beamforming. Team Lead: Jonathan Botts.

ACADEMIC RESEARCH ACTIVITIES

9/19- University of California San Diego, Ph.D. Student

La Jolla, California. Research areas: acoustics, applied mathematics. Develop geometric methods for open-boundary wave simulations. Research topics include spatial audio, numerical simulation, discrete differential geometry, and non-Euclidean geometry. Committee members: Albert Chern (co-chair, CSE), Miller Puckette (co-chair, Music), Melvin Leok (Math), Shahrokh Yadegari (Music), and Sebastian Prepeliță (Reality Labs Research at Meta).

1/17–8/17 University of Edinburgh, Master's Student

Edinburgh, Scotland. Research areas: acoustics, digital signal processing. Developed physics-based numerical simulations of speech sounds and structural vibrations. Research topics included speech acoustics, elastodynamics, modal synthesis, and finite-difference time-domain methods. Advisor: Stefan Bilbao.

1/10–9/13 Wake Forest University, Master's Student

Winston-Salem, North Carolina. Research areas: optics, fluid dynamics. Implemented transverse nanoparticle tracking in surface-isolated laser traps. Research topics included optical trapping, laser beam characterization, and fluid diffusion. Advisor: Keith Bonin.

8/07–8/09 Brigham Young University, Undergraduate Student

Provo, Utah. Research areas: biophysics, structural biology. Analyzed structural changes in lipid bilayers following exposure to a general anesthetic. Research topics included cellular membrane biology and atomic force microscopy. Advisor: David Busath.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

| UCSD | |
|----------|---|
| | |
| MUS 5 | Sound in Time—TA. Spring 2020 (1 term). |
| MUS 6 | Electronic Music—TA. Fall 2020 (1 term). |
| MUS 15 | Popular Music: David Bowie—TA. Winter 2021 (1 term). |
| MUS 15 | Popular Music: Video Game Music—TA. Winter 2020 (1 term). |
| MUS 171 | Computer Music I—TA. Winter 2022 (1 term). |
| MUS 172 | Computer Music II— <i>TA</i> . 2021–2022 (2 terms). |
| UNCSA | |
| | |
| SCI 1100 | General Physics—Instructor. Fall 2012 (1 term). |

TEACHING EXPERIENCE (CONT.)

| <u>WFU</u> PHY 113 PHY 114 | General Physics I (Mechanics)—TA. 2009–2011 (4 terms). General Physics II (E&M)—Tutor. Fall 2010 (1 term). |
|----------------------------------|---|
| BYU PHSCS 105 | General Physics 1 (Mechanics)—Tutor. 2008–2009 (2 terms). |
| PHSCS 106 | General Physics 2 (E&M)—Tutor. Winter 2009 (1 term). |
| PHSCS 121 PHSCS 123 | Principles of Physics 1 (Mechanics)— <i>Tutor</i> . 2008–2009 (2 terms). Principles of Physics 2 (Waves/Thermo)— <i>Tutor</i> . W/Sp 2009 (2 terms). |
| PHSCS 220 | Principles of Physics 3 (E&M)—Tutor. W/Sp 2009 (2 terms) |

PH.D. COURSEWORK

| CSE 167 | Computer Graphics I (Jürgen Schulze) |
|----------|--|
| CSE 169 | Computer Animation—audit (Steve Rotenberg) |
| CSE 274 | Discrete Differential Geometry (Albert Chern) |
| CSE 291 | Physical Simulation—audit (Steve Rotenberg) |
| CSE 299 | Differential Geometry Research (Albert Chern) |
| MUS 206 | Spatial Audio (Shahrokh Yadegari) |
| MUS 206 | Deep Learning for Music Generation (Shlomo Dubnov) |
| MUS 206 | Computational Acoustic Modeling (Tamara Smyth) |
| MUS 270A | Digital Audio Processing (Tamara Smyth) |
| MUS 270B | Analysis of Musical Sound (Miller Puckette) |
| MUS 270C | Compositional Algorithms (Miller Puckette) |
| MUS 270D | Advanced Projects in Computer Music (Puckette/Smyth) |
| MUS 298 | Spatial Audio Research (Puckette/Smyth/Dubnov) |
| MUS 298 | Differential Geometry Research (Miller Puckette) |

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Articles

(1) C. McKell and K. Bonin, "Optical corral using a standing-wave Bessel beam," *Journal of the Optical Society of America B*, Vol. 35, No. 8, 1910–1920, 2018.

Conference Proceedings

(2) C. McKell, "Sonification of Optically-Ordered Brownian Motion," In Proceedings of the International Computer Music Conference (ICMC), Utrecht, Netherlands, September 2016.

Master's Theses

- (3) C. McKell, Real-Time Physical Modeling for Haptic Feedback Rendering, Final Project Dissertation, University of Edinburgh, Acoustics and Audio Group, 2017. (Advisor: Stefan Bilbao).
- (4) C. McKell, Finite-Difference Simulations of Speech with Wall Vibration Losses, Special Project Dissertation, University of Edinburgh, Acoustics and Audio Group, 2017. (Advisor: Stefan Bilbao).
- (5) C. McKell, Confinement and Tracking of Brownian Particles in a Bessel Beam Standing Wave, Master's Thesis, Wake Forest University, Department of Physics, 2015. (Advisor: Keith Bonin).

PUBLICATIONS (CONT.)

Technical Reports

(6) C. McKell, H. Conley, and D. Busath, "AFM Study of Structural Changes in Supported Planar DPPC Bilayers Containing General Anesthetic Isoflurane," Brigham Young University, Paper 827, 2010.

Conference Abstracts

(7) K. Bonin and C. McKell, "Tracking Brownian Particles in a Standing-Wave Bessel Beam 2D Optical Trap," SPIE: Optical Trapping and Optical Micromanipulation, XIV Meeting, 2017.